Guide to the Women and Health Videorecordings
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Women and health videorecordings
1996-1997
V0190
Stanford Channel (Television station: Stanford, Calif.)
2.63 Linear feet 21 videotapes (VHS)
Series of talks and lectures on a broad range of issues related to women and health. In addition to specific medical problems such as cardiovascular health, reproductive tract cancers, osteoporosis, lupus, and autoimmune diseases, subjects include social issues such as drug abuse recovery programs, female circumcision, alternative medicine, health concerns of Asian and Pacific Islander women, Black women, and other specific groups of women; personal stories of illness and recovery; and profiles of women in medicine (Lori Arviso Alvord, assistant professor of surgery at Dartmouth Medical School and former First Navajo surgeon in Gallup, New Mexico).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1999.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford Channel is managed by Stanford University's Information Technology Systems and Services (ITSS), specifically Communication Services. Its broadcasts include telecourses, original programs, lectures, conferences, and Stanford sports events.
Description of the Collection
Series of talks and lectures on a broad range of issues related to women and health. In addition to specific medical problems such as cardiovascular health, reproductive tract cancers, osteoporosis, lupus, and autoimmune diseases, subjects include social issues such as drug abuse recovery programs, female circumcision, alternative medicine, health concerns of Asian and Pacific Islander women, Black women, and other specific groups of women; personal stories of illness and recovery; and profiles of women in medicine (Lori Arviso Alvord, assistant professor of surgery at Dartmouth Medical School and former First Navajo surgeon in Gallup, New Mexico).
Access Terms
Alvord, Lori Arviso.; Alvord, Lori Arviso.; Stanford Channel (Television station: Stanford, Calif.); Minority women--Health and hygiene.; Videorecordings.; Women--Health and hygiene.
Collection Contents
- Videos
  - Cardiovascular Health and Disease Prevention in Women (November 1996), Marcia Stefanick, V190.1; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Clinical Aspects of Rheumatoid Arthritis and Systematic Lupus (March 1997), Elaine Lambert, V190.2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - The Controversy Over Silicone Breast Implants (February 1997), Douglas Ramos, V190.3; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Delancy St. Foundation: An Educational Model for Recovery from Drug Abuse (November 1996), Stephanie Muller, V190.4; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Expedition Inspiration: A Journey to the Summit…Ovarian Cancer (October 1997), Vicki Boriak and Micki Voisard, V190.5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Future Directions in Research (April 1997), Iris Litt, V190.6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - The Health and Well-Being of Asian and Pacific Islander Women (October 1997), Sophie Arao-Nguyen, V190.7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Innovative Pharmacological Therapies: The Example of DHEA for Systematic Lupus (February 1997), Ronald van Vollenhoven, V190.8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Integrating Alternative and Conventional Medicine (October 1996), Adriane Fugh-Berman, M.D, V190.9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Looking for Love in All the Wrong Places (September 1996), Barbara Staggers, V190.10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Management of Female Urinary Incontinence (April 1997), Tom Margolis, V190.11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Providing Quality Health Care for Fat Patients (October 1996), Sally E. Smith, V190.12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Say My Name: Black Women and Health (November 1997), Evelyn White, V190.13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - The Scalpel and the Silver Bear: A Navajo Woman Surgeon’s Story (October 1997), Lori Arviso Alvord, V190.14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Self-Care for Body, Mind, & Spirit (February 1997), The Reverend Lauren Artress, V190.15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - A Strategy for Early Prevention of Osteoporosis (November 1996), Monica Anderson, V190.16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Traditional vs. Western View of Female Circumcision (October 1997), Eiman Mahmoud, V190.17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - What’s Happening to Me? Controversies Surrounding Hormone Replacement Therapy (April 1997), Linda Giudice, V190.18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Women and Autoimmune Diseases (January 1997), Dale Umetsu, V190.19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Women’s Bone Health (October 1996), Dr. Robert Marcus, V190.20; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Women’s Reproductive Tract Cancers: News From a Humanist’s Perspective (October 1997), Katherine O’Hanlon, M.D., V190.21; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)